## Brendan Houng

#### **Contact Information**

Mobile: 0433 507 750 Email: brendan.houng@gmail.com

Web: google scholar, github, CV

### Summary

Data Scientist at Ambulance Victoria. Engaged in analytic sprints to provide insights to internal customers and executive management, communicating complex concepts through visualisations and statistical analyses. Previously, 12 years of combined experience as an applied economist in public policy research and in competition regulation.

#### Education

Ph.D. Economics University of Melbourne (2018) B. Commerce/ B. Software Engineering University of Melbourne (2005)

#### Technical Skills

Statistics/Econometrics (Regressions and Hypothesis Testing), Machine Learning (Clustering and Predictive Models), and Geospatial Mapping. R, Python, Stata, SQL, bash, RMarkdown & Jupyter notebooks, ggplot, matplotlib & d3. See for example R version of Microsoft's TrueSkill algorithm.

## Work Experience

### Insight Specialist, Ambulance Victoria (AV),

Doncaster Melbourne, October 2018 - Present

Engaged in 4-6 week analytic sprints to provide insights for internal customers using a Scrum Agile framework. Jointly built an analytics dashboard with forecasts, maps and visualisations for the Rostering division and conducted statistical data analyses on AV's secondary triage system, which has the aim of diverting low acuity cases away from ambulance services. Identified training opportunities for triage practitioners and highlighted cases where the decision-support software was underrecommending urgency levels.

Currently conducting geographic profiling of Victoria's healthcare and ambulance system, after participating in a design sprint with the Department of Premier and Cabinet's Insight Centre, and partnering with KPMG on a related analytic sprint.

# Research Officer, Melbourne Institute of Applied Economic & Social Research, University of Melbourne, January 2009 - August 2018

Conducted and collaborated on public policy research mostly in the area of Economics of Education for the Victorian Department of Education, and completed a PhD in Economics. Experienced in data analysis, report writing and presentations for academic and general audiences. Refer to CV for further details.

## Graduate/Project Officer, Australian Competition & Consumer Commission, February 2006 - July 2008

Contributed to investigations of merger transactions after completing the graduate program in the telecommunications, energy and mergers branches at the Australian competition regulator. Analysed price data to assess the potential change in local competition arising from proposed transactions.

Last updated: March 31, 2019 Brendan Houng